Gonçalo Cardoso Curriculum Vitae

Front-end / Javascript developer

Personal Information

Full Name Gonçalo Cardoso Borges Ferreira

Date of Birth 7th August 1989

Nationality Portuguese

Phone 00351 91 857 17 46

Email & Website goncalo.cb.ferreira@gmail.com / www.gcardoso.pt

Summary

About me

I'm an enthusiastic Front-end & Javascript developer with a big passion for web and software development. Very professional with a great work ethic and a loyal worker that focuses on the best results. I have a powerful team spirit, a creative mind and a great sense of humour. Technically, in addition to HTML5 and CSS3, I code not only with native object oriented Javascript but I also have experience working with many frameworks and libraries, such as AngularJS, React and jQuery. My front-end development follows the SEO rules and techniques as well as usability guidelines. The mobile compatibility is one of my main concerns so I'm always focused on making my applications work nice and smoothly on mobile devices.

Work Experience

Date March 2015 to present

Company e.near - Nearshore Technology Solutions Computer Software House

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Occupation or position held Team Leader & Javascript Developer

Main responsibilities I'm responsible for the development of mobile casino games, using mainly

Javascript for both frontend (Canvas) and backend (node.js). As a team leader, my main goal is to motivate and push the team members to deliver great casino games, taking the responsability of all decisions made in the proccess. The development

follows an efficient agile method (SCRUM).

Date October 2013 to March 2015

Company StepValue - Web Intelligence Digital Marketing Agency

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Occupation or position held Front-end Developer

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile web

applications, always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript using the latest

frameworks such as Angular JS and Kendo UI. The majority of the web applications

developed were SPA (single-page applications) which made the front-end

development one of the main concerns.

Date October 2010 to October 2013

Company Portugal Telecom Information and Communication Technologies

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Occupation or position held Front-end Developer

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile websites,

always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript. However I was also concerned about cross-

browser compatibility, including the old ones like Internet Explorer 7.

I've worked with major portuguese clients such as Sport Lisboa e Benfica, Portugal Telecom, Portuguese Football Federation and Portuguese Navy. In the last two

projects besides developing my role was to lead the front-end team.

Date February 2008 to August 2008

Company Finepaper - Agência de Produção Gráfica Graphic Design and Production

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Occupation or position held Web Designer Intern

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the development of flash websites using the programming

language ActionScript 3.0, including the company website.

Education

Date October 2007 to July 2010

Course Multimedia Engineering

Degree Bachelor (Bologna Process)

Institution Instituto Superior de Tecnologias Avançadas

Final Grade 15 / 20

Main Subjects Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Web Development, Database

Management, Maths and Statistics, Video and Animation

Skills & Competences

Development HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 (Functional, Modular and Object Oriented), Node.js,

Single Page Applications, UX, Progressive Enhancement, Graceful Degradation,

Cross-browser Compatibility, Canvas, Flux & Redux, Git & SVN

APIs REST APIs, Facebook Graph API, Google Maps API, Twitter API

Javascript frameworks React, AngularJS, Kendo UI, jQuery (UI and Mobile)

Software PHPStorm, WebStorm, Sublime, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe

Illustrator

Soft skills Enthusiastic, creativity, problem solving, teamwork, decision making, quick learning,

time management, team leadership, determination, responsibility, patience,

proactivity, accuracy, result-driven

Interests Swimming, walking, running, music, digital world, advertising, marketing, politics,

design, user experience, web development, programming, computer science